Literacy Volunteers of America (LVA) Records
Literacy Volunteers of America (LVA) Records
- Media, audiovisual
  - Audiotape, cassettes
    - [unidentified] F-2, Riposo Studios, Syracuse, New York, lva_133; running time 19:52; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 46)
    - [unidentified] G-2, Riposo Studios, Syracuse, New York, lva_134; running time 9:58; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 46)
    - [unidentified] Seg. 5, Riposo Studios, Syracuse, New York, lva_135; running time 28:46; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 46)
    - [unidentified] Seg. 6, Riposo Studios, Syracuse, New York, lva_136; running time 25:00; 1/8 inch audio cassette (Box 46)
  - Films
    Films listed without a box number should be requested using the ID number, for example "lva_061."
    - It Takes Only Two - negative and print, lva_393
    - It Takes Only Two (backup copy) - negative and print, lva_394
    - [unidentified] R-3 - Sect. 4, lva_390; Film: 16mm
    - [unidentified] R-4 Sec - 5 & 6 WYES “Literacy Volunteers” Neg A Roll Only, lva_391; Film: 16mm
    - [unidentified] R5 Sect 7-8-9, lva_392; Film: 16mm
    - [unidentified] Session I - Section 1, Less 2, B & C (Negative), lva_388; Film: 16mm
    - [unidentified] Sec 2 + 3 Lit. Vol. R2, Pict. 900-15, Track 750-1, lva_389; Film: 16mm
    - [unidentified] Session IV, Neg. Sections 10-11, lva_106; Film: 16mm
  - Filmstrips
    - Basic Reading Tutor Training Workshops, 6 rolls (Box 41)
  - Slides
    Slides were extremely difficult to identify. In the inventory below, everything written on a slide box has been transcribed.
    - "Additional Training Techniques for Special Reading Problems" (BK3, BRW-K3), 3 boxes (Box 41)
    - "Basic Reading Tutor Training Workshop"
      - Segment F(a). "Assessment and Goal Setting", 1987; 2 boxes (Box 41)
      - Segment F(b). "Goal Analysis and Lesson Planning", 1987; 2 boxes (Box 41)
      - Segment G(2), 1987; 2 boxes (Box 41)
      - Miscellaneous, 1987; 1 box (Box 41)
    - Basic Reading Workshop, 3-ring binder (Box 43)
    - Basic Reading Workshop Segment K1, 3-ring binder (Box 43)
    - "Comp. & Study" (BL-2, BL-3), 2 slide carousels (Box 43)
    - "Comprehension and Study Skills" (BL3 and Part 2), 2 boxes (Box 41)
    - ESL, 3-ring binder (Box 42)
    - "ESL Overview", 1 slide carousel (Box 42)
    - ESL Workshop
      - "ESL-A", 2 boxes (Box 41)
      - "ESL-B", 2 boxes (Box 41)
      - "ESL-C", 2 boxes (Box 41)
      - "ESL-D", 2 boxes (Box 41)
      - "ESL-E, 2 boxes (Box 41)
      - "ESL-F", 2 boxes (Box 41)
      - "ESL-G", 2 boxes (Box 41)
      - "ESL-H", 2 boxes (Box 41)
      - "Seg.5 F1", 1 box (Box 41)
    - "Flora", 2 boxes (Box 41)
    - Goals and Lessons Plans; Assessment and Goal Setting; Teaching Language Skills; Formal Assessment; Goal Analysis and lesson Planning, 3-ring binder (Box 42)
    - "Human Interest Stories", 3 boxes (Box 41)
    - Intercultural Communication (E1), 1 box (Box 41)
    - Language Experience; Sight Words; Word Patterns, 3-ring binder (Box 42)
    - "PR. To Read, to Speak, to Live", 1 box (Box 41)
    - Teacher Training Workshop ("BRW Replacement A, B, C), 1976; 1 box (Box 41)
    - Tutor Training Workshop
      - Segment A. Introduction (BA), 2 boxes (Box 41)
      - Segment B. The Experience Story (Language Experience) (BB), 4 boxes (Box 41)
      - Segment C. Sight Words (BC), 2 boxes (Box 41)
      - Segment D. Learning to Read by…Phonics (BD), 2 boxes (Box 41)
      - Segment E. Learning to Read by…Word Patterns (BE), 4 boxes (Box 41)
      - Segment G. Applying all techniques (BG), 2 boxes (Box 41)
      - Segment I. Lesson Plans and Goals (BI), 2 boxes (Box 41)
      - Segment J. Student Motivation and Reinforcement (BJ), 4 boxes (Box 41)
    - Miscellaneous slides, 2 boxes (Box 41)
  - Videorecordings
    - American Library Association (ALA)
      - Literacy tape #1 - Dr. Anna Marie Larson, Chicago Sheraton, 09/25/1975; lva_089; 1/2 inch videotape (Box 52)
      - Literacy tape #2 - Dr. Anna Marie Larson, Chicago Sheraton, 09/25/1975; lva_090; 1/2 inch videotape (Box 52)
      - Literacy tape #3 - Dr. Anna Marie Larson, Mrs. Jinx Crouch, Chicago Sheraton, 09/25/1975; lva_091; 1/2 inch videotape (Box 52)
      - Reel #I ALA 9/26/75, 09/26/1975; lva_092; 1/2 inch videotape (Box 52)
      - Reel #II ALA 9/26/75, 09/26/1975; lva_093; 1/2 inch videotape (Box 52)
      - Reel #III ALA 9/26/75 - American Library Assoc. Tape #3, 09/26/1975; lva_094; 1/2 inch videotape (Box 52)
      - Reel #IV ALA 9/26 “CYR”, 09/26/1975; lva_095; 1/2 inch videotape (Box 52)
      - Reel #V ALA 9/26, 09/26/1975; lva_096; 1/2 inch videotape (Box 52)
    - Basic Reading, Introduction, lva_100; running time 28:20; 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic (Box 52)
    - Basic Reading Tutor Training Workshop “Introduction”, 03/31/1983; lva_107; running time 28:20; 1 inch videotape: SMPTE Type C (Box 53)
    - Goals and Lesson Plans, Tutor Training Workshop, Segment 6 1985, 07/12/1985; lva_099; running time 60:00; 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic (Box 52)
    - LVA (Field Service Copy), lva_101; running time 12:00; 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic (Box 52)
    - LVA - Sub Master - “Basic Reading - Intro”, lva_105; running time 28:30; 1 inch videotape: SMPTE Type C (Box 53)
    - Lang. Exp. Approach Dec. 12, 1984, 12/28/1984; lva_108; running time 28:18; 1 inch videotape: SMPTE Type C (Box 53)
    - Literacy Volunteers Awards Ceremony
      - Dorothy Clark - Discussion on pins, Tutor (BR & ESL) Award, Administrative Award; D. Clark - Intro to RJ Colvin Awards., lva_102; 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic SP (Box 52)
      - Ends - Dorothy Clark Summarizing Ruth J. Colvin Awards - Includes Tutor Awards (no student), lva_103; 3/4 inch videotape: U-matic SP (Box 52)
    - Literacy Workshop, San Francisco July 3, 1975
      - Tape 1 J. Nelson, J. Coleman, B Wedgeworth, 07/03/1975; lva_097; 1/2 inch videotape (Box 52)
      - Tape 2, 07/03/1975; lva_098; 1/2 inch videotape (Box 52)
    - Public Affairs - Basic Reading, ESL, WTVH 5, Syracuse, New York, 08/12/1977; lva_104; running time 2:30; Cut 1 - Basic Reading Prog. - tutor; 2 - General; 3 - Basic Reading Prog. - student; 4 - ESL Prog. - student; 5 - ESL Prog. - tutor; 2 inch videotape: Quad (Box 53)